Alexander Macdonald

16 Wisp Green, Edinburgh, EH15 3QX

□ (+44) 7445438343 | ■ alexander.mac.93@gmail.com | ★ amcdn.dev | □ AJM93 | 匝 axmacdonald

"Build projects around motivated individuals. Give them the environment and support they need, and trust them to get the job done."

Summary_

Lead Mobile Developer managing a small team in a software house working fully remote for the past year. 5+ years experience specializing in cross-platform mobile development in React Native, back-end/infrastructure & web development. I love sharing my knowledge with colleagues and getting stuck in to new technologies & seeing how they can improve workflow. Excellent communication skills with the ability to explain technical details to non-technical stakeholders.

Skills_

DevOps Bitrise, Jenkins, AWS, Docker, Vagrant, Serverless

Back-end Express, Apollo, Django, REST, GraphQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Front-end React, Redux, RxJS, Handlebars, Styled Components, HTML5, SASS

Mobile React Native, PWAs, Native iOS, Native Android Programming Javascript, Node.js, Swift, Java, Python, Bash

Technologies Git, Stripe, Firebase, Twillio, Cloudflare, Jira, Confluence, Trello, Sketch

Experience _____

Vidatec Ltd Fully Remote Nov. 2020 - Present LEAD MOBILE DEVELOPER

• Managing a team of 4 people, providing support & assigning work

- · Helping grow team, conducting technical interviews & onboarding new starts
- Heavily involved in our graduate program
- Deploying multiple projects on AWS (EC2, Elastic Beanstalk, Lambda)
- · Serverless projects with GraphQL Apollo Server API & Next. js web app Deployed to AWS Lambda functions
- Setting up CI/CD for new projects with Bitrise & Bitbucket pipelines
- Multiple Stripe integrations
- · Running workshops with potential clients to explore their ideas and outline suitable technologies for implementation

REACT NATIVE DEVELOPER Jul. 2019 - Nov. 2020

- · Software house working on a variety of apps for many clients, some being used by as many as 5 million people
- iOS & Android apps built with React Native
- Creating iOS & Android Native Modules where a clients 3^{rd} party tool only has native SDKs (e.g. MappedIn)
- · Many apps would have an accompanying CMS/API (Node.js, Knex.js, Express, Handlebars, MySQL)
- · White-Labeling our exisiting products to assist in sales

Shot Scope - Golf Performance Tracker

Edinburgh, Scotland

Jul. 2017 - Jul. 2019

- Solo developer of the native iOS app
- · Required BLE to connect to, receive performance data & upload it from all of the Shot Scope golf performance tracking wearables
- Performed initial R&D to move mobile development to React Native
- Supported other developers in the transition to React Native
- Worked on the C# based API hosted on Azure
- Introduced Jenkins for CI/CD

Agenor Technology Edinburgh, Scotland Jun. 2016 - Jul. 2017

APPLICATION DEVELOPER

IOS DEVELOPER

• Maintaining the Iceflo iOS app and API

- Creating the native Android version of the Iceflo app
- Creating the next-gen version of Iceflo web app (Moving from APEX to React.js with a Java API)
- Used Twillio to create chat within the next-gen Iceflo app

IOS DEVELOPER Jun. 2015 - Jun. 2016

- · Initially a 12 week summer internship, extended through my final year of university
- Developed Iceflo native iOS application
- Created API written in Java with a PLSQL database hosted on an Glassfish server

ALEXANDER MACDONALD · CURRICULUM VITAE

The University of Dundee

Dundee, Scotland

 Lab Tutor/Mentor
 2014 - 2016

- Helped 1^{st} , 2^{nd} & 3^{rd} year students complete lab tasks & assignments
- Assignments included: Data structures with C++, Web development with Java, Games programming with Unity/C# & Networking
- Tasked with providing longer 1 1 mentoring sessions for struggling students

CO-FOUNDER & ORGANIZER OF HACKDEE 2015

Mar. 2015 - Apr. 2015

- Securing sponsorship from tech companies, namely NCR & J.P. Morgan
- Organised food, merch, challenges & prizes from sponsors
- Ensured the 70 person event ran smoothely on the day

Education

The University of Dundee

Dundee, Scotland

FIRST CLASS HONOURS IN APPLIED COMPUTING

2013 - 2016

- Awarded the NCR prize for exceptional performance in my $3^{rd} \& 4^{th}$ year
- Regular Hackathon attendee & organiser winning JP Morgan's prize at Stackshack 2015

The University of the Highlands and Islands

Inverness, Scotland

2011 - 2013

HND IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT